ALI SALEH

- +02001097450187
- Mansoura
- in linkedin.com/in/Ali-saleh17

OBJECTIVE

A fresh Law graduate who is ambitious, enthusiastic and possesses a genuine interest and understanding of law, interested in working with a reputed law firm or a company's legal department to apply my knowledge for intensive judiciary cases and to increase my experience and skills as a lawyer.

EDUCATION & AFILLIATIONS

Bachelor of Law

Mansoura University

<u></u> 2018 - 2022

Cumulative Grade: Very Good with honors (87.42%)

Student Member

Chartered Institute of Arbitrators (CIArb)

Mul 2022 - Present

SKILLS & ABILITES

- Analytical
- Team Worker
- Documents Review
- Legal Research
- Computer Skills (MS Word/ PowerPoint)

EXPERIENCE

Legal intern

Peb 2022- Mar 2022

- Legal analysis of on-going cases before the Egyptian courts.
- Drafting and Reviewing Memorials.

VIRTUAL INTERNSHIPS

Banque Misr – Summer Intern (Pioneers Program)

Mul 2022 – Jul 2022

- Introducing the components of the banking system and the different types of banks within the Egyptian banking sector.
- Information about Cash Loan & Mortgage Products.

Virtual Experience Program - Baker McKenzie

March 1982 - Jun 2022 - Jun 2022

Completing two practical task modules in:

- Understanding the unexpected situation and report it by leaving a voicemail.
- Drafting a letter to the defendant's solicitor and Consent orders to extend the deadline requiring the plaintiff to file and serve its lay evidence.

Internship Experience UK - Commercial Law - Bright Network

Mulicipal Programme Programme 1985 March 1985 March 1985 Programme 1985 March 1985 Programme 198

Completing two primary tasks:

- Prepare a summary of the arbitral process for the client who has not been involved in arbitral proceedings before.
- Review and amend a draft request for arbitration by preparing a table of amendments to the request for arbitration.

UK Virtual Learning Programme - White & Case LLP

Apr 2021 - Apr 2021

Completing three primary tasks:

- Putting a structure chart for a transaction using PowerPoint slide.
- Delivering short presentation explaining one strategy commonly used to mitigate counterparty credit risk.
- Drafting board resolutions and a prospectus.

Bright Network Experience UK - Law

Dec 2020 – Jan 2021

- Outlining the key parts of the acquisition transactions.
- Completing table of amendments for a non-disclosure agreement.
- Summarizing the effective factors in the due diligence.
- Power pointing comparison of pros and cons of Arbitration and Litigation.

Banque Misr – Summer Intern

Aug 2020 - Dec 2020

- Introducing the components of the banking system and the different types of banks within the Egyptian banking sector.
- Develop dynamic and more understanding listening skills for customers.
- How to identify problems, know their causes, propose solutions, and solve the problem.
- Information about Cash Loan & Mortgage Products.

LANGUAGES

Arabic: Mother-Tongue

English: Fluent